nasafcu.com 2010-06-23

# NASA Federal - Privacy Pledge

|  |   
|  | ONLINE CHAT | CONTACT US | [SEARCH](http://www.nasafcu.com/l2.aspx?ci=928) ||  [](https://ebranch.nasafcu.com/)  
  
---|---  

Privacy Policy   

## Keeping Your Information Safe and Secure

**For 60 years, NASA Federal Credit Union has served members through the long-standing tradition of people helping people, and we continue that tradition today.**

You can count on NASA Federal Credit Union to provide you with quality financial services, competitive rates, professional service and to protect your privacy and security every step of the way. 

This page outlines the NASA Federal Credit Union Privacy Policy and describes how we use and protect your information. We believe that protecting your privacy is one of the most important parts of the service we provide to you. 

At NASA Federal Credit Union, we value your relationship and we work every day to honor the trust you place in us. Thank you for choosing NASA Federal Credit Union for your financial needs. 

## Our Commitment To You

  * We do not sell or share member information with outside parties who may want to offer you their products and services. You do not have to take any action or instruct us to keep your information confidential. We will protect your privacy automatically.
  * We safeguard member information.
  * We are committed to protecting member information in every transaction, at every level of the Credit Union. For this purpose, we have designed procedures, standards and technology, which are described here.
  * We are committed to helping you protect your privacy every day. This brochure includes tips to help you protect yourself from identity theft and limit direct marketing from outside companies. 

## Making Security a Priority

Keeping financial information secure is one of NASA Federal Credit Union’s most important financial responsibilities. 

**NASA Federal Credit Union is committed to protecting the security and integrity of member information through procedures and technology designed for this purpose.**

For example:

  * Employees are authorized to access member information only when they have a business reason to know this information. They are bound by our code of conduct, which includes standards to protect member confidentiality and are subject to disciplinary action if they fail to do so.
  * Policies and procedures covering the physical security of workplaces and records are properly maintained.
  * Physical, electronic and procedural safeguards meet or exceed federal standards regarding the protection of member information.
  * Independent contractors and outside companies who work with us are required to adhere to strict privacy standards through their contracts with us.
  * The latest technology, such as backup files, virus detection and eradication software, firewalls, and other computer software and hardware, is used to protect against unauthorized access or alterations to member data. 

**NASA Federal Credit Union collects and maintains information to service your account, save you time and better respond to your needs. In the course of serving you, we collect information about you from a variety of sources, which may include:**

**Application Information** — information you provide to us on applications or forms, such as your assets, income and credit obligations.  
**Consumer Report Information** — information from credit reports including credit history and creditworthiness.  
**Transaction and Account Experience** — information about your transactions and account experiences with NASA Federal Credit Union, such as account balances, payment history and credit card usage.  
**Information from Outside Sources** — information from outside sources regarding your employment, credit and other relationships. 

As required by the USA PATRIOT Act, we also collect information and take actions necessary to verify your identification. 

**Information we collect may be used by NASA Federal Credit Union, as well as by authorized third parties (described below) to:**

  * **Protect your accounts** from unauthorized access and identity theft.
  * **Process your requests** such as loan applications, purchases and ATM withdrawals.
  * **Service your accounts** by issuing checks, ATM cards and account statements.
  * **Keep you informed** about financial services of interest to you. 

**We may disclose the information we collect, as described previously, with nonaffiliated third parties that act on our behalf.**

All companies that act on our behalf are contractually obligated to keep the information we provide to them confidential and to use the member information we share only to provide the services we ask them to perform. These companies may include companies that perform support services for us, such as data processors, statement processors, check printers, card issuers, or companies that help us market NASA Federal Credit Union services. 

In other situations, we may also disclose member information we collect to third parties as permitted or required by law. In these situations, third parties may include credit bureaus, government entities, courts or other entities (in response to subpoenas and other legal processes) and those with whom you have allowed us to share information. 

Some state laws may impose additional restrictions on the disclosure of member information in those states to nonaffiliated third parties for certain purposes. 

This disclosure applies to members who have, or have had a member relationship with NASA Federal Credit Union and those individuals who do business with us. 

The policies and practices described in this disclosure are subject to change, but we will communicate any significant changes to you as required by applicable law. The policies and practices described in this disclosure replace all previous notices or statements regarding this subject. 

## Web Site Privacy

As a general policy, we do not automatically collect personal information from our Web site users. We do collect and store information on the domain used to access our Web site, the Internet address of the Web site from which a user links to the Credit Union's Web site and the date and time of the visit to our Web site. This information is used only to measure the number of visitors to our Web site and the route a user travels while within the Credit Union's Web site to better serve users in improved design and site navigation. 

## Member-Only Areas

Personal identification, such as your account number and password, is collected when a valid Credit Union member with active Credit Union account(s) enters the secure online banking area of the Credit Union's Web site. This information enables the Credit Union to regulate access of this information to those who request such access and those entitled to perform transactions on these account(s). 

## Cookies

Our Web site may use cookies (small pieces of information sent by our Web server to a visitor's Web browser that reminds our site about the user the next time he or she visits). We do not store confidential or sensitive information in cookies. We use cookies only to enhance a member’s online banking session and ease navigation through our Web site. 

For certain applications, such as online banking, cookies are required to help protect the privacy of a member's transactions by, for example, automatically terminating the online session if the member forgets to log out. Cookies cannot be used to capture a user's email address, obtain data from the user's hard drive or gain confidential or sensitive information about the user. Additionally, cookies cannot be read by a Web site other than the one that set the cookie. Some Web sites, however, use cookies to obtain information from the user's browser. The user has the option to set his or her browser to notify before accepting a cookie to control whether a cookie is accepted or rejected. 

## Online Forms

NASA Federal Credit Union provides several online forms (for example, loan application or check order) to better serve the needs of members. Personal information provided via any Credit Union online form is used only to process the member's request for service. These forms are transmitted via secured means. However, if the user is concerned about the security of transmitting this information via the Internet, the member is encouraged to contact the Credit Union directly at **301-249-1800** or **1-888-NASA-FCU** (1-888-627-2328) to transmit the information another way. 

## E-mail Communication

We may use personal information you transmit to us to respond to inquiries for service or information, or improve the service the Credit Union provides. Since e-mail communication may not be secure against interception by unauthorized individuals, users may want to seek alternatives to e-mail when it is necessary to provide sensitive or personal information. 

**NASA Federal Credit Union will not transmit sensitive or personal information that can compromise or violate a user's privacy when communicating via e-mail.**

## Guarding Your Own Information

NASA Federal Credit Union recommends that you take the following precautions to guard against the disclosure and unauthorized use of your account and personal information: 

  * Never provide personal information, such as your Social Security Number, account or credit card information over the phone unless you have initiated the call. 
  * Ensure that your computer has the most current virus detection and/or firewall protection. 
  * Safeguard your ATM, credit and debit cards. 
  * Memorize Personal Identification Numbers (PINs) and refrain from writing PINs, Social Security numbers and credit card numbers where they can easily be found. 
  * Keep your financial records and personal information in a secure location. 
  * Never preprint your Social Security Number and driver’s license number on your checks. 
  * Review your account statements regularly and report any suspicious charges. 
  * Check your credit at least once each year. 
  * Carry your Social Security Card only when necessary. 
  * Cancel unused credit cards. 
  * Tear up or shred unused preapproved credit offers, credit card receipts, cancelled checks, pay stubs and financial documents. 
  * Report lost or stolen checks, credit and debit cards immediately. 

## Assistance to Victims of Identity Theft

If you suspect that someone has had unauthorized access to your account with us, or access to personal identifying information such as your Social Security Number or credit card information, please contact us immediately at **301-249-1800** or **1-888-NASA-FCU** (1-888-627-2328) so we can take action to protect you. 

If you think your identity has been stolen, you should also:

**Place a fraud alert on your credit** file at any one of the three credit bureaus:

Experian: **www.experian.com** , 1-888-397-3742  
Equifax: **www.equifax.com** , 1-800-685-1111  
TransUnion: **www.transunion.com** , 1-800-888-4213

**Close the accounts** that you know or believe have been tampered with or opened fraudulently.

**File a police report** and submit a copy to your creditors and others that may require proof of the crime.

**File your complaint with the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) atwww.ftc.gov/idtheft** or call the FTC’s identity theft hotline at **1-877-IDTHEFT** (1-877-438-4338). 

## Reducing Direct Marketing From Other Sources

If you would like to reduce the amount of advertising you receive from companies outside NASA Federal Credit Union, contact the following agencies: 

Direct Marketing Association, Inc.  
1120 Avenue of the Americas  
New York, NY 10036

212-768-7277, ext. 1500 

You can also remove your name from these lists by visiting the DMA consumer assistance site at **www.dmachoice.org.**

## National Consumer Credit Reporting Agencies

If you would like your name removed from lists for pre-approved offers of credit or insurance obtained from the major credit reporting agencies, go to **www.optoutprescreen.com** or call **1-888-5OPTOUT** (1-888-567-8688). 

The information you provide is confidential and will only be used to process your request. 

## National Do Not Call Registry

Help eliminate unwanted and uninvited calls from telemarketers to your home when you register your telephone numbers – at no cost – with the National Do Not Call Registry. 

Register your residential and cell phone numbers online at **www.donotcall.gov** or by calling **1-888-382-1222**. While this will stop most calls, you may still receive calls from businesses with which you have a business relationship. 

|
